## Chunlei Peng, Ph.D. Candidate

CONTACT

VIPS Lab

INFORMATION

State Key Laboratory of ISN
School of Electronic Engineering

Phone: +86 15829916976

Email: clp.xidian@gmail.com

Xidian University, No. 2 South Taibai Road

Homepage:

Xi'an, China, 710071

http://chunleipeng.com/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Machine learning, computer vision, image processing, and pattern recognition with applications to **heterogeneous image transformation** (e.g. face sketch-photo synthesis) and **heterogeneous face recognition** (e.g. matching viewed/composite/forensic sketches to face photos, and matching near-infrared/thermal-infrared images to visible light face images).

EDUCATION EXPERIENCES

Sep. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Visiting Graduate Student in Biomedical Engineering Department

Duke University, Durham NC, USA Supervised by Prof. Sina Farsiu

Sep. 2012 - Present

Ph.D. Candidate in Intelligent Information Processing

School of Electronic Engineering Xidian University, Xi'an, China

Adviser: Xinbo Gao

Sep. 2008 - July 2012

**Bachelor** in Electronic Information Engineering

School of Electronic Engineering Xidian University, Xi'an, China

Undergraduate thesis: "Adaptive Markov Random Field based Face Sketch-

Photo Synthesis" (Outstanding undergraduate thesis)

Rank: 6/543

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

- Multimedia Information Processing and Analysis, supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 61125204), participant, 2012.01-2015.12
- Generalized Sparse Representation based Heterogeneous Face Image Transformation and Quality Assessment, supported by National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No.61172146), participant, 2012.01-2015.12
- Heterogeneous Image Transformation and Quality Assessment, supported by the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (Grant No. JB149901), participant, 2014.01-2015.12
- On Cross Media Heterogeneous Image Transformation and Recognition based on Big Data, Transverse Research Projects, participant, 2013.11-2015.04
- Transductive Learning based Heterogeneous Face Image Transformation from An Arbitrary Profile, supported by the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities (Grant No. K50513100009), participant, 2013.01-2013.12

PUBLICATIONS .Journals

- [1] Chunlei Peng, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, and Jie Li, "Graphical Representation for Heterogeneous Face Recognition," *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (IEEE TPAMI)*, Accepted, 2016. (Graphical representations are obtained through Markov networks, with spatial information taken into consideration. Leading performance is achieved on multiple heterogeneous face recognition scenarios.)
- [2] Chunlei Peng, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Dacheng Tao, Xuelong Li, and Jie Li, "Multiple Representations based Face Sketch-Photo Synthesis," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (IEEE TNNLS)*, Accepted, 2015. (We adaptively learn the combination weights of multiple representations, and the synthesis process is robust to different lighting conditions and backgrounds on real-world forensic sketches and mug shots.)
- [3] **Chunlei Peng**, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, "Superpixel-based Face Sketch-Photo Synthesis," *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (IEEE TCSVT)*, Accepted, 2015. (Superpixel is firstly introduced into face sketch-photo synthesis scenario, which can take inherent face structure into consideration.)
- [4] **Chunlei Peng**, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, and Jie Li, "Sparse Graphical Representation based Discriminant Analysis for Heterogeneous Face Recognition," arXiv preprint arXiv:1607.00137, 2016. (Adaptive sparse graphical representations are obtained. We further develop a spatial partition-based discriminant analysis framework including row-based, column-based, and learning-based strategies.)
- [5] Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, **Chunlei Peng**, and Chengyuan Li, "Triple Space Fusion based Face Image Recognition," *Pattern Recognition and Artificial Intelligence*, vol. 28, no. 9, pp. 811-821, 2015. (Invited, in Chinese) (Review the recent advances on heterogeneous face recognition based on triple space fusion, i.e. the fusion of the physical space, the information space, and the cognitive space.)

## Conference

- [1] **Chunlei Peng**, Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, and Jie Li, "Face Recognition from Multiple Stylistic Sketches: Scenarios, Datasets, and Evaluation," *European Conference on Computer Vision workshop on Visual Analysis of Sketches*, 2016. **(Oral)**
- [2] **Chunlei Peng**, Jie Li, Nannan Wang, and Xinbo Gao, "Multi-View Representation based Face Sketch Synthesis," *ACM International Conference on Internet Multimedia Computing and Service (ICIMCS)*, 2014, pp. 307-312.
- [3] Decheng Liu, **Chunlei Peng**, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, and Xinbo Gao, "Composite Face Sketch Recognition based on Components," *International Conference on Wireless Communications and Signal Processing (WCSP)*, Accepted, 2016.
- [4] Xinye Yu, Nannan Wang, **Chunlei Peng**, Jie Li, and Xinbo Gao, "Adaptive Representation-based Face Sketch Synthesis," *International Conference on Intelligence Science and Big Data Engineering (IScIDE)*, Accepted, 2016.

## **Book Chapter**

[1] Nannan Wang, Shengchuan Zhang, Chunlei Peng, Jie Li, and Xinbo Gao, "Face Sketch Recognition via Data-driven Synthesis," Biometrics in Forensic Science, Springer, 2015.

## **PATENTS**

- [1] Xinbo Gao, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Forensic Sketch based Face Recognition," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410166300.7, 2014.
- [2] Jie Li, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Multiple Features Fusion based Image Synthesis," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410165469.0, 2014.
- [3] Xinbo Gao, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Graphical Representation based Face Sketch-Photo Recognition," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201510397326.7, 2015.
- [4] Xinbo Gao, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Superpixel based Face Sketch Synthesis," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201510395890.5, 2015.
- [5] Xinbo Gao, Wenjun Ren, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Image Quality Assessment based Synthesized Face Image Recognition," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410133868.9, 2014.
- [6] Xinbo Gao, Yanting Hu, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, Wenjun Ren, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Cascade Linear Regression based Image Super-Resolution", Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410766467.7, 2014.
- [7] Jie Li, Mingjin Zhang, Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Shengchuan Zhang, Chunlei Peng, et al., "Support Vector Machine based Sketch Style Classification," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410330945.X, 2014.
- [8] Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Nannan Wang, Jie Li, Mingjin Zhang, Yanting Hu, Chunlei Peng, and Wenjun Ren, "Greedy Search based Face Sketch Synthesis," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410818175.3, 2014.
- [9] Xinbo Gao, Nannan Wang, Wenjun Ren, Jie Li, Yanting Hu, Shengchuan Zhang, Mingjin Zhang, and Chunlei Peng, "Feature Similarity based Synthesized Face Sketch Quality Assessment," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201410771613.5, 2014.
- [10] Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Jie Li, Feng Wang, Xinye Yu, Mingjin Zhang, Chunlei Peng, and Yanting Hu, "One Target Sketch based Face Sketch Synthesis," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201510109196.2, 2015.
- [11] Nannan Wang, Xinbo Gao, Shengchuan Zhang, Jie Li, Feng Wang, Xinye Yu, Mingjin Zhang, Chunlei Peng, and Yanting Hu, "Single Photo-Sketch Pair based Face Sketch Synthesis," Chinese Patent Pending, No. 201510109027.9, 2015.

ΑV

WARDS	Special Scholarship from China Internet Development Foundation	2016
	National Scholarship from Ministry of Education	2015
	Outstanding Graduate Student, Xidian University	2014
	First-Class Graduate Scholarship for PhD candidate, Xidian University	2014
	Second-Class Graduate Scholarship for PhD candidate, Xidian University	2013

	Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis, Xidian University	2012
	Third Prize in ACM-ICPC, Xidian University	2011
	Outstanding Student, Xidian University	2009
Professional Activity	Review for Neurocomputing (Elsevier) from 2015; Review for 27th IEEE International Conference on Tools with Artificial gence (ICTAI), Vietri sul Mare, Italy, November, 2015.	Intelli-
SKILLS	Proficient in Matlab, C/C++, Qt, OpenCV, Latex; Familiar with Python, Java	a